Zaray Salas López

15 Barton Court, Churchtown, Co. Dublin 14 Address:

Tel No.: 085 772 93 16

E-mail: salas-lopez@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/zaray-salas-lópez-26797945

GitHub: https://github.com/zaraysalas

SEEKING FOR FULL-TIME JOB OPPORTINITIES 2022:

Stamp 2: Eligible to work 20 hours in term time and full-time over the summer period.

PERSONAL PROFILE:

Technology graduate to be (Level 8) in 2022. With 9 years of experience in Import / Export sector where I got negotiation, companyoriented, problem-solving and management skills. Plus 5 years in Hospitality industry where I gained client-focused, team-working skills. Looking for opportunities as inter or entry level position in the Technology sector, specifically in Data Analytics or software development areas. Trained and confident in basic IT knowledge and fundamentals of Data Analytics and Python programming where I continue improving my knowledge and capabilities

KEY SKILLS:

PROGRAMMING: Java (Eclipse, NetBeans), Python (Jupyter, Google Collab, RStudio)

WEB DEVEPMENT: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap

NETWORKING: Routing & Switching Protocols

DATABASE ADMINISTRATION: MySQL

CLOUD TECHNOLOGIES: Heroku, AWS

OTHER APPLICATIONS: Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) tools, Microsoft Office Suite, G-Suite, Google Docs,

Google Drive, OneDrive

EDUCATION & TRAINING:

EB CONTION & TRAINING.				
2018 – 2022	Bachelor of Science (Honours) in Computing and IT			
Address:	CCT College Dublin, 30-34 Westmoreland Street, Dublin 2			
Core Modules:	Machine Learning for Artificial Intelligence / Data Exploration, Preparation, Visualization & Communication / Object-Oriented Design Patterns / Network Forensics / Interactive Web Applications			
Project Work:	Most recent project I took part of was a team work where we explore the performance of different classifier algorithms and then with two models determinate if a SMS is Spam or not. To know more details refer to my video in the follow link: https://youtu.be/FZS2iOUFV5Q			
2021	Diploma in Predictive Data Analytics			
Address:	CCT College Dublin, 30-34 Westmoreland Street, Dublin 2			
Core Modules:	Regression / Validation and Testing / Text Analytics / Data visualization			
Project Work:	Together with Diploma in Python Programming gave me the basic knowledge to code in platforms like Jupyter(Anaconda) and R-Studio. Visualize information through graphs, manipulate it to perform Machine Learning and Deep Learning Algorithms.			
2021				

2021

Diploma in Python Programming

Address: CCT College Dublin, 30-34 Westmoreland Street, Dublin 2

Core Modules: Python environment / Flow Control / Array types / Working with files / Dictionary and sets / Functions / Modules

and packages / Regular expressions / Highlights of the standard library / Python classes

2012 - 2014Master in International Logistics - Universidad De La Salle Bajío (México)

Information Technology apply to Logistics / International Logistic Strategies / Maritime Transport / Logistic Core Modules:

Distribution System / Customs Processes / Evaluation of Customs Projects

Zaray Salas Lopez | salas-lopez@hotmail.com

2001 – 2005 Bachelor of International Trade - Universidad De La Salle Bajío (México)

Core Modules: International Finances / International Business & Accounting / Sales Management / Marketing / International

Negotiation / Foreign Trade Logistics / Law applied to International Business

Project Work: Over the seven years working in this industry, I participate and developed different projects such as the viability of

having a warehouse in Panama, negation with new suppliers and improving relationship with existing ones, between

others.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

While studying full-time for my Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, I have been funding my college fees and living expenses in Dublin, by working part-time in a variety of positions in the hospitality sector as a Chef and Barista.

WING IT RESTAURANT

63a South Great George's St D2

2019 - 2020

Restaurant stablished in Ireland since 2012 that specialized in New York style wings.

Chef

Successfully maintaining 12.5 minutes average food preparation.

Effectively training 90% of new staff in the kitchen.

BEWLEY'S GRAFTON ST.

78/79 Grafton St. D2

2018 - 2019

Coffee and tea company founded in 1840.

Counter Assistant / Barista / Cashier

Achieve a promotion in 2018 within first year in the company.

Successfully perform 3 different positions within the company.

LUSEMAX

León, Guanajuato, Mexico

April – July 2018

Purchasing Executive

Successfully hiring and training an employee in one month to take over my position before the ending of my temporary contract with the company.

Increased use of the Enterprise Resource Planning software by 10%.

Improve the catalogue by 20%.

Develop a relation with an University to hire recently graduates / students in their last term and

hiring one student as a result of the previously mention program.

Diagnosing areas where the company was losing money.

2015 - 2017

During this time, I attended English courses in Dublin getting the Cambridge Certificate in Advanced English in February 2018 achieving a B2 level.

Additionally, I travelled through several countries around Europe increasing confidence speaking English.

I did volunteer work in St. Patrick's Festival 2016 assisting public along the parade route and setting venues.

Supporting myself with part-time jobs such as child-minder and kitchen porter.

Taking a barista course.

GRUPO NAZAN, S.A. DE C.V.

León, Guanajuato, Mexico

November 2012 - April 2015

Mexican company with shoes stores in several cities around Mexico where I was buying their products from several manufactures and then allocating them into the different stores depends on their sales records.

Purchasing Executive

GRUPO INTERCOPA, S.A. DE C.V.

León, Guanajuato, Mexico

February 2010 - May 2012

Mexican company that mainly sales materials for buildings projects.

Import Administrator

Zaray Salas Lopez | salas-lopez@hotmail.com

Produced a viability study of setting a Warehouse in Panama as a link from the containers coming from China to Mexico which determined the business idea was not feasible.

ECODELI COMERCIAL, S.A. DE C.V. León, Guanajuato, Mexico March 2008 – August 2009

Mexican manufacturer and provider of cleaning products in a B2B model.

Purchasing Executive

Successfully fulfilling 100% of stock required by sale department on a high demanded product during the influenza crisis in Mexico in 2009.

COTEXCA, S.A. DE C.V. León, Guanajuato, Mexico July 2006 – April 2008

Mexican company which manufacture synthetic leather used to produce belt and handbags specially.

Import Administrator

Ensured 100% of orders entering to Mexico from Italy and USA compile and benefit from the taxes reduction programs.

PERSONAL PROJECTS/CONTINUED PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT:

German course	https://open.spotify.com/show/3QiX0ZkjILyGWmpemack	46 hrs	2021 - Ongoing	
	WB?si=IU6dlOJvQ3y 330NDJDMiQ			
German course	https://www.duolingo.com		2021 - Ongoing	
Italian Course	https://www.duolingo.com		2021 – Ongoing	
Machine Learning	https://www.aws.training		2020 - Ongoing	
Data Analytics	https://www.aws.training		2021 – Ongoing	
Data Scientist	https://www.awseducate.com/student	35 hrs	2021 - Ongoing	
Web Development Engineer	https://www.awseducate.com/student	50 hrs	2021	
MEMBERSHIPS/SUBSCRIPTIONS/FOLLOWING:				
Member of Amazon training program – AWS training	https://www.aws.training		2018	
Member of AWS Educate	https://aws.amazon.com/education/awseducate		2020	
Gradireland	https://gradireland.com		2020	
INTERESTS:				

TED Business Podcast

https://open.spotify.com/show/1hAE2QpiA1yOBJ6QyVFqpI?si=CMKP7vCjRf6Ar846J91JGQ

Bill Gates & Rashida Jones ask big questions Podcast

https://open.spotify.com/show/4LUx6oYWDzNYRBhSF7T7cX?si=KKztUThSRuSlmjmgjwZBGQ

Tech talk with Jess Kelly Podcast

https://open.spotify.com/show/4gFUOEvLsZ0Ovucxlj2mRJ?si=g6MWBnjJRdWvztp_Cd71Kw